Naruto.
(ホタル)ナルトさん…。
I...
あの…。
(ナルト)大丈夫。
You'll be fine.
ありがとう…。
Thank you.
What's the matter, Naruto?
(ヤマト)どうした？ ナルト。
Sorry, Captain Yamato.
ヤマト隊長… 悪いけど
先に行っててくれねえか？
Would you mind going on ahead
without me?
I'm returning to that village.
オレは あの里に戻る。
Return?
(サイ)戻る？
Something keeps...bothering me.
どうしても… 気になるんだ。
I can't help but think about
the way those villagers looked at her.
《村人たちの あの視線…》
Wait, Naruto!
おい！ 待つんだ！
《クソッ！ 何か 嫌な感じがする！》
Damn, I have a bad feeling
about this.
遠路はるばる
疲れただろう？ ホタル。
You must be exhausted after
your long journey, Hotaru.
さぁ…。
Come...
あの…。
Umm...
ついてきなさい。
Follow me.
頭領のヤツ どういうつもりだ！
What is the Chief thinking?
本当にここで かくまうのか？
Does he really intend to
shelter her here?
冗談だろ！
もし何かあったら オレたちまで…。
You've got to be kidding.
If something happens, we'll get--
Hush! You talk too much.
シッ！ 言いすぎだよ！
Should I have not come back?
私… 戻ってきては
いけなかったんでしょうか？
そんなことない。
Of course not.
You're finally home.
せっかく 帰ってきたんだ。
ゆっくり休みなさい。
You must get some rest.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
うむ では。
Well then...
やっと会えたな。
We finally meet the granddaughter
of En no Gyoja.
役行者の孫娘。
Who's there?!
何者です!?
(アカボシ)お前が この里を頼るのは
わかっていたからな。
We knew you would rely
on this village.
あなたたち 砦を襲った…!?
You're the ones who attacked the fort!
Someone, help! Bandits!
助けてください！ 賊です！
おじさん！
ここを開けてください!!
Uncle, please open the door! Uncle!
おじさん！ 誰か～!!
Somebody!
ムダだ！
It's useless.
Now, hand over the Forbidden Jutsu.
さぁ 禁術を渡してもらおうか。
イヤです！
No!
(ナンゴウ)手間とらせるな！
Don't give us trouble!
(ベンテン)おいおい…
女性はもう少し 優しく扱え。
Hey, hey... Be more gentle
when handling a lady.
(チュウシン)ヘヘヘヘ！
テメエの吐く言葉じゃねえだろ。
You should talk.
Bro.
兄貴！
これが 例の秘術か…。
So this is the hidden jutsu in question...
ゴホッ ゴホッ！
ウヘヘヘ！ 仕込みかよ。
So it was rigged, eh?
チッ！ ナマイキな！
Sassy kid...
追え！ 娘を逃がすな！
After her! Don't let her get away.
《まさか 土蜘蛛の里にまで
手が回っていたなんて…。
To think they had already
taken steps
in the Tsuchigumo village...
とにかく この場を離れないと…》
I have to get away from here.
森に逃げたか…。
So she ran into the forest...
ヘヘヘヘ！ 見つけたぜ お嬢ちゃん。
Found you, girlie.
水遁 水乱波！
Water Style: Raging Waves!
ハッ！ そんなチンケな術に
やられてんなよ チュウシン。
Don't let a petty jutsu like that
bring you down, Chushin.
うるせえ！
ちょっと驚いただけだ！
Shut up! She just caught me
by surprise, is all.
Playtime is over. Tell me.
さて 忍者ごっこは ここまでだ。
教えろ。 禁術はどこにある？
Where is the Forbidden Jutsu?
うぜえな。
ヘヘ。
What a pain.
今のうちに吐いたほうがいいぜ。
I'd talk now if I were you.
そのベンテン… ツラは女みてえだがよ
切れると怖いぜ。
Benten might look like a girl,
but he's scary when he's mad.
言えません！ あれは
私たちの最後の希望なんです！
I won't talk!
That is my people's last hope.
あ～ もう めんどくせえや！
Geez... This is getting ridiculous.
どうしても言いたくねえなら➡
If you don't want to talk,
I'll help you get into the mood.
しゃべりたくなるように
手伝ってやるよ。
殺すなよ。
ヘヘ…。
Don't kill her.
ソイツは この小娘次第だ。
That's all up to her.
What?!
なに!?
(ウタカタ)騒がしいなぁ。
これじゃ居眠りもできやしねえ。
What's all this racket?
Can't a guy even take a nap?
ウタカタ様！
Sir Utakata!
キサマ 生きてやがったのか。
You! You're still alive?
あのとき 確かに…。
We got you back there for sure!
フフ… ご期待にそえず悪かったな。
Well, sorry to disappoint you.
別に アンタらと
やりあいたいわけじゃないが➡
It's not like I wanna fight you guys...
コイツには オレも用があってね。
But I have business with her too.
The Successor's Wish
え？ あの子がいなくなった？
どういうことだってばよ！
What? She's gone?!
What's up with that?!
私どもにも よくわからんのです。
I'm not sure myself.
This is where I hid Hotaru.
ここに ホタルを
かくまっていたんですが➡
突然 大きな音がして➡
Then there was a loud noise
and when I rushed over, she was...
駆けつけたときには もう。
わかった。 オレも捜す。
All right. I'll help you find her.
捜索が終わったところを
教えてくれ。
Tell me where you've searched already.
あぁ いや… その…。
Well, um... We haven't started
the search yet.
捜索をするのは
実は これからでして。
えっ…。
What?!
なんで すぐ捜さねえんだ？
Why didn't you search
for her immediately?
建物が こんなんなって
何かあったに決まってんのに！
Judging by the damage,
it's obvious something happened!
ええ… ですが…。
Yes...but...
何 考えてんだ！
What's wrong with you?!
Isn't she one of your people?!
あの子は
里の仲間じゃねえのかよ！
(ヤマト)よさないか ナルト。
Enough, Naruto.
ここで もめても
しかたがないだろう。
Yelling won't help.
ヤマト隊長… どうして？
Captain Yamato.
What are you doing here?
ボクらも気になってね。
追いかけてきたんだが➡
We were also worried,
so we rushed back.
正解だったようだ。
It seems we were right.
最後に彼女を見たのは
いつです？
When did you last see her?
あぁ… 少し前です。
Just a while ago.
あなた方がホタルを連れてきてから
すぐ ここに案内して…。
After you brought Hotaru here,
I showed her to this room.
だとすると まだ
そう時間は経っていないな。
Then not much time has passed.
急ごう。 ナルト。
けど！
Let's hurry, Naruto.
But...
今は 彼女の保護が優先だよ。
Her safety is our main concern
right now.
ウタカタ様
助けに来てくれたんですね。
Sir Utakata, you came to save me!
そういうわけじゃないんだが➡
That's not quite the case,
but we'd better do something here.
とりあえず
この場を なんとかしないとな。
なんだ コイツ…。
What's with this guy?
あん時 オレらの術を
くらったはずなのに…。
I thought our jutsu hit him that time.
性懲りもなく
お宝をかすめ取ろうって魂胆かよ。
Are you scheming to steal
our treasure away from us?
させるか。
I won't let you.
酸藤花！
Acid Flower!
ナンゴウ 戻れ！
Nango, come back!
ありゃ 外したか。
Oh... It missed.
この！
Why you--!
Surround him!
We'll bring him down this time.
囲め！ 今度こそ ヤツをしとめる！
陣の外に！
He's outside our formation!
あばよ。
させるか。
So long.
Not so fast!
ウタカタ様！
Sir Utakata!
逃げ足が速いな。
He's fast.
連中 まだ遠くへは
行ってねえはずだ。
They can't have gone far.
Let's go after them.
すぐに追いかけて。
やめておけ。
Forget it.
頭。
なぜです？
Boss.
Why? Are you just gonna let
our treasure get away?
お宝を みすみす逃す気ですか。
これは 霧のビンゴ・ブック。
This is the Mist's Bingo Book.
なかなか おもしろいヤツが
絡んできたもんだぜ。
We've stumbled across
a very interesting guy.
ってことは アイツ これに
のるような賞金首ってことか。
Meaning his head's worth enough
to be in this book?
すげえ 5,000万両。
Wow... 50 million ryo.
こりゃついてる。
We're in luck.
The girl's jutsu is worth a fortune,
and now this.
小娘の術だけでも すげえのに
唸るほどのカネが入ってくるぜ。
We'll be rolling in money.
でも こんだけの値が
ついてるってことは➡
But with a bounty this high,
he's bound to be a formidable foe.
アイツ 相当なやり手なんじゃ…。
ハッ！ 怖気づいてんじゃねえ。
Hah! Don't get cold feet now!
This is our big chance.
せっかくのチャンスだってのによ。
なんだと… オレはただ。
What? I'm just...
おい！ 少し黙らないか。
それで どうします？ 頭。
Hey! Pipe down.
So what'll we do, Boss?
そうだな。
Let's see...
《オレのせいだ… あの時…》
It's my fault. I...
《オレがすぐに戻ってれば…》
I should've returned right away.
１つ 聞いてもいいですか？
Can I ask you a question?
ボクたちの任務は➡
Our mission was to protect the girl
彼女を土蜘蛛の里まで
警護することでしたよね。
until she reached
Tsuchigumo village safely, right?
そのつもりだったんだけどね。
That was supposed to be it.
でも正確にいえば➡
But if we can't completely guarantee
that she's safe,
きちんと彼女の身の安全が
確保できなければ➡
the mission had no meaning.
意味がないんだよ。
この任務は
もともと ３代目火影と➡
This mission is based on a treaty
which was drawn up
土蜘蛛一族の
役行者の間で結ばれた➡
by the Third Hokage and En no Gyoja
of the Tsuchigumo Clan.
ある盟約によるものだ。
So if the current Tsuchigumo Clan
cannot protect her,
だからもし 今の土蜘蛛一族に
彼女を護る力がないのなら➡
then it's our job to do so.
こちらで保護するしかない。
サイ この辺りで
広域探索をかけてくれるか。
Sai, can you scan the entire area
and search for her?
わかりました。
Understood.
忍法 超獣偽画。
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll.
《待ってろ 必ず見つけてやる》
Hold on...
We'll find you for sure!
Sir Utakata, where are we?
ウタカタ様… ここは？
うわ～！
Wow...
高い！
So high!
この辺でいいか。
This should be good.
I thought I was done for.
もう ダメかと思いました。
You are amazing, after all.
やっぱりウタカタ様は
すごいです。
勘違いするな。
Don't get me wrong.
I didn't mean to save you.
オレは別に
お前を助けたわけじゃない。
では なぜ来てくれたのです？
そりゃ➡
Then why did you come?
Well... Let's just say
I became curious
ヤツらが しつこく欲しがる
その禁術ってのに➡
about this Forbidden Jutsu
those guys seem to want so badly.
興味が出てきたからさ。
ウソです ウタカタ様は
そんな方じゃありません。
You're lying. You're not like that.
わからないぜ。
Never can tell.
There's not a person in the world
カネの匂いが嫌いなヤツは
いないからな。
who doesn't love
the smell of money.
今更 悪ぶってもムダです。
Don't pretend to be a villain.
はぁ…。
どうも お前といると
調子が狂うな。
You have a knack for putting me
off balance.
しかし
これからどうする気だ？
But what will you do now?
その術を狙うのは
連中だけじゃない。
Those guys aren't the only ones
who'll target that jutsu.
この先も きっと
わんさか現れるぞ。
Others are bound to turn up.
そうですね。
You're right.
そのためにも
もっと強くならなくっちゃ。
That's why I must get stronger.
だから 私を弟子に…。
おっと。
That's why I want to become
your stu--
Stop right there. I'm not listening.
その話なら ごめんだ。
だいたい ジイさんの形見だか
何だか知らねえがなぁ➡
Besides, this keepsake of
your grandfather or whatever...
何で そうまでして守ろうとする。
Why are you so determined to protect it?
それは…。
Well...
師匠の思いに こたえるためです。
It's to honor the wishes
of my master.
おじい様は
私の最初の師匠でもありました。
Grandfather was also my first master.
師匠と弟子は互いに思い合うもの。
A master and student must
be one in thought.
だから おじい様が
果たせなかった夢➡
That's why I want to fulfill the dream
that my grandfather could not.
土蜘蛛一族を復興させるために➡
In order to restore
the Tsuchigumo Clan,
私は この術を
失うわけには いかないんです。
I cannot lose this jutsu.
ふっ 思い合うか。
Hmph... One in thought?
くだらねえ妄想だな。
Such a stupid delusion.
あの どちらへ。
Where are you going?
これ以上
お前に付き合う義理はないからな。
I'm under no obligation
to stick around.
師弟ごっこなら
よそでやってくれ。
If you wanna play master and student,
go somewhere else.
ごっこじゃありません。
It's not play!
I'm serious about you!
私 本気であなたを思ってます！
ウタカタ様を師匠と呼びたいんです！
I want to call you my master!
お前には止められないぜ。
You can't stop me, you know.
わかっています
でも 私の気持は変わりません。
I know that.
But my feelings won't change.
だから…。
That is why...
え…。
Huh?!
バッ バカ！ お前 いきなり何を!?
I-Idiot! What're you doing?!
ウタカタ様に
見ていただきたいのです。
I want you to see me...
私のすべてを…。
Everything about me.
Hotaru...you...
ホタル お前…。
なんてことを！
How could they?
このことは
誰も知りません。
No one knows about this...
でも ウタカタ様には
隠したくなかった。
But I didn't want to hide it from you.
お願いです ウタカタ様。 私…。
Please, Sir Utakata...
言うな！
- I...
- Don't say it!
(ウタカタ)チクショウ…。
Damn it!
秘術 切雨。
Hidden Jutsu: Kirisame.
しまった！
Shoot!
この雨 やはり切雨か。
As I thought...
This rain is Kirisame...
ウタカタ。
Utakata.
もはや お前に逃げ道はない。
There is no escape for you now.
何ですか!?
What's going on?
これ以上
里を待たせるわけにはいかない。
We cannot keep the village
waiting any longer.
アンタらも ホントにしつこいな。
下がれ ホタル。
You guys sure are persistent.
Stay back, Hotaru.
水遁 水流鞭！
Water Style: Water Whip!
キャ！
ホタル！
Hotaru!
もう一度言う。
抵抗をやめて 我々と来い。
I'll say it once more.
Cease resisting and come with us.
おかしなマネをすれば
この娘の命はないぞ。
If you try anything, this girl will die.
ウタカタ様…。
Sir Utakata...
いっとくが ソイツは関係ない
赤の他人だ。
Let me make it clear that
she is nothing to me.
どうなろうと
オレの知ったこっちゃない。
I couldn't care less what happens.
そうか なら試してみよう。
I see. We'll see about that.
効果は
それなりにあるようだな。
I see that worked.
Now return to the village with us.
我らとともに里に戻れ。
何回聞いても答えは同じだ。
No matter how many times you ask,
the answer will be the same.
では しかたがない。
Then we have no choice.
雷遁 地走り。
Lightning Style: Earth Flash!
ぐわっ!!
ウタカタ様！
悪く思うな。
Sir Utakata!
Don't take this personally.
我々は どうしてもヤツを
連れ帰らねばならんのだ。
We absolutely must take him
back to our village.
こんなひどいこと
やめてください！
Such cruelty... Please stop.
どうせ この程度で
死にはしない。
This isn't enough to kill him.
少し 力をそいでおくだけだ。
I'm just restricting a little of
his strength.
もうやめて！
いったい ウタカタ様が➡
Stop it! Just what did Sir Utakata
do anyway?!
何をしたって言うんですか！
ヤツは 師匠殺しのウタカタ。
Utakata is a heinous criminal
who killed his master
里を抜けた大罪人だ。
これよりヤツを拘束する。
準備にかかれ！
はっ！
螺旋丸！
なにっ!?
《何だ？》
人質とるなんて
汚ねえヤツらだ！
ナルトさん！
待たせて悪かったってばよ。
プハー！ 食った食った！
(キバ)やっぱ 冬は鍋だよな。
(シノ)白菜がうまかった。
んじゃ そろそろ
シメのラーメンといくか。
あっ ゴキブリ！
そこだ!!
なにすんだよ。
一寸の蟲にも五分の魂。
むやみに殺生をするな。
それに あれが出るのは➡
この部屋を不潔にした
住人のせいだといえる。
でも 放っとくのはごめんだぜ。
だな。 １匹見つけると➡
仲間が100匹いるって言うし。
わかった。
オレが ひと肌脱ごう。
今から 蟲寄せの秘術を行い➡
彼らを正しく森に帰す。
ああ。 んじゃ
ひとつよろしく。
いいだろう。
秘術 蟲寄せ！
(ミッシェル)ルーシィ姉さん どう？
古代文字 見つかった？
(ルーシィ)ううん 全然駄目。
(エルザ)ルーシィ 仕事だ。
(グレイ)金塊を奪ったやつらを
捕まえに行くんだってよ。
もしかして またケツプリ団？
さあな 行きゃわかんだろ。
ごめん 今回はパス。
鉄の棒から浮かび上がった
文字の解読が進まないの。